[
  {
    "Chapter 1": {
      "1": {
        "Question": "1.She hadn\u2019t eaten all day, and by the time she got home she was______.a. blightedb. confutativec. ravenousd. ostentatiouse. blissful",
        "a": {
          "option": "blighted",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to suffer a blight\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. affected by blight; anything that mars or prevents growth or prosperity\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "confutative",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. able to be refuted\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "ravenous",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. extremely hungry\n2. devouring or craving food in great quantities\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "ostentatious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. intended to attract notice and impress others\n2. (of a display\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "blissful",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. completely happy and contented\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. Ravenous (adj.) means extremely hungry."
      },
      "2": {
        "Question": "2.The movie offended many of the parents of its younger viewers byincluding unnecessary ______ in the dialogue.a. vulgarityb. verbosityc. vocalizationsd. garishnesse. tonalityChapter 1",
        "a": {
          "option": "vulgarity",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the quality of lacking taste and refinement\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "verbosity",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an expressive style that uses excessive or empty words\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "vocalizations",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the sound made by the vibration of vocal folds modified by the resonance of the vocal tract\n2. the use of uttered sounds for auditory communication\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "garishness",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. tasteless showiness\n2. strident color or excessive ornamentation\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "tonality",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. any of 24 major or minor diatonic scales that provide the tonal framework for a piece of music\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. Vulgarity (n.) means offensive speech or conduct."
      },
      "3": {
        "Question": "3.His neighbors found his ______ manner bossy and irritating, andthey stopped inviting him to backyard barbeques.a. insentientb. magisterialc. reparatoryd. restorativee. modest",
        "a": {
          "option": "insentient",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. devoid of feeling and consciousness and animation\n2. or insensate\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "magisterial",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. of or relating to a magistrate\n2. offensively self-assured or given to exercising usually unwarranted power\n3. used of a person's appearance or behavior; befitting an eminent person\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "reparatory",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "restorative",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a medicine that strengthens and invigorates\n2. a device for treating injury or disease\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. tending to impart new life and vigor to\n2. promoting recuperation\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "modest",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by simplicity; having a humble opinion of yourself\n2. not large but sufficient in size or amount\n3. free from pomp or affectation\n4. not offensive to sexual mores in conduct or appearance\n5. low or inferior in station or quality\n6. humble in spirit or manner; suggesting retiring mildness or even cowed submissiveness\n7. relatively moderate, limited, or small\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. Magisterial (adj.) means overbearing or offensively self-assured."
      },
      "4": {
        "Question": "4.Steven is always ______ about showing up for work because hefeels that tardiness is a sign of irresponsibility.a. legibleb. tolerablec. punctuald. literale. belligerent",
        "a": {
          "option": "legible",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. (of handwriting, print, etc.\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "tolerable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. capable of being borne or endured\n2. about average; acceptable\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "punctual",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. acting or arriving or performed exactly at the time appointed\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "literal",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a mistake in printed matter resulting from mechanical failures of some kind\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. being or reflecting the essential or genuine character of something\n2. without interpretation or embellishment\n3. limited to the explicit meaning of a word or text\n4. avoiding embellishment or exaggeration (used for emphasis\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "belligerent",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. someone who fights (or is fighting\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. characteristic of an enemy or one eager to fight\n2. engaged in war\n3. or warring\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. Punctual (adj.) means arriving exactly on time."
      },
      "5": {
        "Question": "5.Candace would ______ her little sister into an argument by teasingher and calling her names.a. advocateb. provokec. perforated. lamentee. expunge",
        "a": {
          "option": "advocate",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a person who pleads for a cause or propounds an idea\n2. a lawyer who pleads cases in court\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. push for something\n2. speak, plead, or argue in favor of\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "provoke",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. call forth (emotions, feelings, and responses\n2. evoke or provoke to appear or occur\n3. provide the needed stimulus for\n4. annoy continually or chronically\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "perforate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make a hole into or between, as for ease of separation\n2. pass into or through, often by overcoming resistance\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having a hole cut through\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "lamente",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "expunge",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. remove by erasing or crossing out or as if by drawing a line\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. To provoke (v.) is to incite anger or resentment; to call forth afeeling or action."
      },
      "6": {
        "Question": "6.The dress Ariel wore ______ with small, glassy beads, creating ashimmering effect.a. titillatedb. reiteratedc. scintillatedd. enthrallede. striated",
        "a": {
          "option": "titillated",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. touch (a body part\n2. excite pleasurably or erotically\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. feeling mild pleasurable excitement\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "reiterated",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. to say, state, or perform again\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "scintillated",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give off\n2. reflect brightly\n3. emit or reflect light in a flickering manner\n4. physics: fluoresce momentarily when struck by a charged particle or high-energy photon\n5. be lively or brilliant or exhibit virtuosity\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "enthralled",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. hold spellbound\n2. hold spellbound\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. filled with wonder and delight\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "striated",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. mark with striae or striations\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. To scintillate (v.) means to emit or send forth sparks or little\ufb02ashes of light, creating a shimmering effect; to sparkle."
      },
      "7": {
        "Question": "7.Being able to afford this luxury car will ______ getting a better-paying job.a. maximizeb. recombinantc. reiterated. necessitatee. reciprocate2",
        "a": {
          "option": "maximize",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make as big or large as possible\n2. make the most of\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "recombinant",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a cell or organism in which genetic recombination has occurred\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. of or relating to recombinant DNA\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "reiterate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. to say, state, or perform again\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "necessitate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. require as useful, just, or proper\n2. cause to be a concomitant\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "reciprocate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. act, feel, or give mutually or in return\n2. alternate the direction of motion of\n"
        },
        "Answer": "d. To necessitate (v.) means to make necessary, especially as a result."
      },
      "8": {
        "Question": "8.Levina unknowingly ______ the thief by holding open the elevatordoors and ensuring his escape.a. coercedb. proclaimedc. abettedd. sanctionede. solicited",
        "d": {
          "option": "sanctioned",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give sanction to\n2. give authority or permission to\n3. give religious sanction to, such as through on oath\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. conforming to orthodox or recognized rules\n2. formally approved and invested with legal authority\n3. established by authority; given authoritative approval\n"
        },
        "a": {
          "option": "coerced",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. to cause to do through pressure or necessity, by physical, moral or intellectual means\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "proclaimed",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. declare formally; declare someone to be something; of titles\n2. state or announce\n3. affirm or declare as an attribute or quality of\n4. praise, glorify, or honor\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. declared publicly; made widely known\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "abetted",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. assist or encourage, usually in some wrongdoing\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "solicited",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make a solicitation or entreaty for something; request urgently or persistently\n2. make amorous advances towards\n3. approach with an offer of sexual favors\n4. incite, move, or persuade to some act of lawlessness or insubordination\n5. make a solicitation or petition for something desired\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. To abet (v.) means to assist, encourage, urge, or aid, usually anact of wrongdoing."
      },
      "9": {
        "Question": "9.Shakespeare, a(n) ______ writer, entertained audiences by writingmany tragic and comic plays.a. numericb. obstinatec. dutifuld. proli\ufb01ce. generic",
        "a": {
          "option": "numeric",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. of or relating to or denoting numbers\n2. measured or expressed in numbers\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "obstinate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. persist stubbornly\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. tenaciously unwilling or marked by tenacious unwillingness to yield\n2. stubbornly persistent in wrongdoing\n3. resistant to guidance or discipline\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "dutiful",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. willingly obedient out of a sense of duty and respect\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "proli\ufb01c",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "generic",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. wine that does not meet the minimum qualifications and standards for use of a designation by appellation of origin (where the grapes are grown\n2. made-up\n3. such as `vin rouge', `vino rosso', `rotwein', `red wine', etc.\n4. as `vin ordinaire', `vin de table', `vino da tavola', `tafelwein', `table wine', etc.\n5. any product that can be sold without a brand name\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. relating to or common to or descriptive of all members of a genus\n2. (of drugs\n3. applicable to an entire class or group\n"
        },
        "Answer": "d. Proli\ufb01c (adj.) means abundantly creative."
      },
      "10": {
        "Question": ".10.I had the ______ experience of sitting next to an over-talkativepassenger on my \ufb02ight home from Brussels.a. satisfactoryb. commendablec. gallingd. acceptablee. acute",
        "a": {
          "option": "satisfactory",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. giving satisfaction\n2. meeting requirements\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "commendable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. worthy of high praise\nAdverb meaning(s):\n1. in an admirable manner\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "galling",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. become or make sore by or as if by rubbing\n2. irritate or vex\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. causing irritation or annoyance\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "acceptable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. worthy of acceptance or satisfactory\n2. judged to be in conformity with approved usage\n3. meeting requirements\n4. adequate for the purpose\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "acute",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a mark placed above a vowel to indicate pronunciation\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having or experiencing a rapid onset and short but severe course\n2. extremely sharp or severe\n3. having or demonstrating ability to recognize or draw fine distinctions\n4. of an angle; less than 90 degrees\n5. ending in a sharp point\n6. of critical importance and consequence\n7. or critical\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. Galling (adj.) means irritating, annoying, or exasperating."
      },
      "11": {
        "Question": ".11.Prince Phillip had to choose: marry the woman he loved and ______his right to the throne, or marry Lady Fiona and inherit the crown.a. reprimandb. upbraidc. abdicated. winnowe. extol",
        "a": {
          "option": "reprimand",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an act or expression of criticism and censure\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. rebuke formally\n2. censure severely or angrily\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "upbraid",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. express criticism towards\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "abdicate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give up, such as power, as of monarchs and emperors, or duties and obligations\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "winnow",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the act of separating grain from chaff\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. separate the chaff from grain by using air currents\n2. blow on\n3. select desirable parts from a group or list\n4. blow away or off with a current of air\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "extol",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. praise, glorify, or honor\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. To abdicate (v.) means to formally relinquish or surrender power,of\ufb01ce, or responsibility."
      },
      "12": {
        "Question": ".12.If you will not do your work of your own ______, I have no choicebut to penalize you if it is not done on time.a. predilectionb. coercionc. excursiond. volitione. infusion",
        "b": {
          "option": "coercion",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the act of compelling by force of authority\n2. using force to cause something to occur\n"
        },
        "a": {
          "option": "predilection",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a predisposition in favor of something\n2. a strong liking\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "excursion",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a journey taken for pleasure\n2. wandering from the main path of a journey\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "volition",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the capability of conscious choice and decision and intention\n2. the act of making a choice\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "infusion",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a solution obtained by steeping or soaking a substance (usually in water\n2. the process of extracting certain active properties (as a drug from a plant\n3. usually in water\n4. (medicine\n5. a fluid or drug or electrolyte\n6. as by gravitational force\n7. the act of infusing or introducing a certain modifying element or quality\n"
        },
        "Answer": "d. Volition (n.) means accord; an act or exercise of will."
      },
      "13": {
        "Question": ".13.After sitting in the sink for several days, the dirty, food-encrusteddishes became ______.a. malodorousb. prevalentc. imposingd. perforatede. emphatic",
        "d": {
          "option": "perforated",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make a hole into or between, as for ease of separation\n2. pass into or through, often by overcoming resistance\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having a hole cut through\n2. having a number or series of holes\n"
        },
        "a": {
          "option": "malodorous",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having an unpleasant smell\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "prevalent",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. most frequent or common\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "imposing",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. compel to behave in a certain way\n2. impose something unpleasant\n3. impose and collect\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. impressive in appearance\n2. used of a person's appearance or behavior; befitting an eminent person\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "emphatic",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. spoken with emphasis\n2. sudden and strong\n3. forceful and definite in expression or action\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. Malodorous (adj.) means having a foul-smelling odor."
      },
      "14": {
        "Question": ".14.Giulia soon discovered the source of the ______ smell in the room:a week-old tuna sandwich that one of the children had hidden inthe closet.a. quaintb. fastidiousc. clandestined. laconice. fetid",
        "a": {
          "option": "quaint",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. strange in an interesting or pleasing way\n2. very strange or unusual; odd or even incongruous in character or appearance\n3. attractively old-fashioned (but not necessarily authentic\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "fastidious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. giving careful attention to detail; hard to please; excessively concerned with cleanliness\n2. having complicated nutritional requirements; especially growing only in special artificial cultures\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "clandestine",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. conducted with or marked by hidden aims or methods\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "laconic",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. brief and to the point; effectively cut short\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "fetid",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. offensively malodorous\n"
        },
        "Answer": "e. Fetid (adj.) means having a foul or offensive odor, putrid."
      },
      "15": {
        "Question": ".15.After making ______ remarks to the President, the reporter wasnot invited to return to the White House pressroom.a. hospitableb. itinerantc. enterprisingd. chivalrouse. irreverent",
        "a": {
          "option": "hospitable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. favorable to life and growth\n2. disposed to treat guests and strangers with cordiality and generosity\n3. having an open mind\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "itinerant",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a laborer who moves from place to place as demanded by employment\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. traveling from place to place to work\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "enterprising",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by imagination, initiative, and readiness to undertake new projects\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "chivalrous",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. being attentive to women like an ideal knight\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "irreverent",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. showing lack of due respect or veneration\n2. characterized by a lightly pert and exuberant quality\n3. not revering god\n"
        },
        "Answer": "e. Irreverent (adj.) means lacking respect or seriousness; notreverent."
      },
      "16": {
        "Question": ".16.With her ______ eyesight, Krystyna spotted a trio of deer on thehillside and she reduced the speed of her car.a. inferiorb. keenc. impressionabled. ductilee. conspiratorial4",
        "a": {
          "option": "inferior",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. one of lesser rank or station or quality\n2. a character or symbol set or printed or written beneath or slightly below and to the side of another character\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. of or characteristic of low rank or importance\n2. of low or inferior quality\n3. written or printed below and to one side of another character\n4. having an orbit between the sun and the Earth's orbit\n5. lower than a given reference point\n6. falling short of some prescribed norm\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "keen",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a funeral lament sung with loud wailing\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. express grief verbally\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having or demonstrating ability to recognize or draw fine distinctions\n2. intense or sharp\n3. very good\n4. painful as if caused by a sharp instrument\n5. having a sharp cutting edge or point\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "impressionable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. easily impressed or influenced\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "ductile",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. easily influenced\n2. capable of being shaped or bent or drawn out\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "conspiratorial",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. relating to or characteristic of conspiracy or conspirators\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. Keen (adj.) means being extremely sensitive or responsive;having strength of perception.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
      },
      "17": {
        "Question": ".17.With a(n) ______ grin, the boy quickly slipped the candy into hispocket without his mother\u2019s knowledge.a. jaundicedb. nefariousc. stereotypicald. sentimentale. impartial",
        "a": {
          "option": "jaundiced",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. distort adversely\n2. affect with, or as if with, jaundice\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. affected by jaundice which causes yellowing of skin etc\n2. showing or affected by prejudice or envy or distaste\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "nefarious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. extremely wicked\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "stereotypical",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. lacking spontaneity or originality or individuality\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "sentimental",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. given to or marked by sentiment or sentimentality\n2. effusively or insincerely emotional\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "impartial",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. showing lack of favoritism\n2. free from undue bias or preconceived opinions\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. Nefarious (adj.) means wicked, vicious, or evil."
      },
      "18": {
        "Question": ".18.Her ______ display of tears at work did not impress her new boss,who felt she should try to control her emotions.a. maudlinb. meritoriousc. precariousd. plausiblee. schematic",
        "a": {
          "option": "maudlin",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. effusively or insincerely emotional\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "meritorious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. deserving reward or praise\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "precarious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. affording no ease or reassurance\n2. fraught with danger\n3. not secure; beset with difficulties\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "plausible",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. apparently reasonable and credible, and therefore convincing\n2. given to or characterized by presenting specious arguments\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "schematic",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. diagram of an electrical or mechanical system\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. represented in simplified or symbolic form\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. Maudlin (adj.) means excessively and weakly sentimental ortearfully emotional."
      },
      "19": {
        "Question": ".19.Johan argued, \u201cIf you know about a crime but don\u2019t report it, youare ______ in that crime because you allowed it to happen.\u201da. acquittedb. steadfastc. tenuousd. complicite. nulli\ufb01ed",
        "a": {
          "option": "acquitted",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. pronounce not guilty of criminal charges\n2. behave in a certain manner\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. declared not guilty of a specific offense or crime; legally blameless\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "steadfast",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by firm determination or resolution; not shakable\n2. firm and dependable especially in loyalty\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "tenuous",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having thin consistency\n2. very thin in gauge or diameter\n3. lacking substance or significance\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "complicit",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "nulli\ufb01ed",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "Answer": "d. Complicit (adj.) means participating in or associated with aquestionable act or a crime."
      },
      "20": {
        "Question": ".20.The authorities, fearing a ______ of their power, called for amilitary state in the hopes of restoring order.a. subversionb. premonitionc. predilectiond. infusione. inversion",
        "a": {
          "option": "subversion",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. destroying someone's (or some group's\n2. the act of subverting; as overthrowing or destroying a legally constituted government\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "premonition",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a feeling of evil to come\n2. an early warning about a future event\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "predilection",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a predisposition in favor of something\n2. a strong liking\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "infusion",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a solution obtained by steeping or soaking a substance (usually in water\n2. the process of extracting certain active properties (as a drug from a plant\n3. usually in water\n4. (medicine\n5. a fluid or drug or electrolyte\n6. as by gravitational force\n7. the act of infusing or introducing a certain modifying element or quality\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "inversion",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the layer of air near the earth is cooler than an overlying layer\n2. abnormal condition in which an organ is turned inward or inside out (as when the upper part of the uterus is pulled into the cervical canal after childbirth\n3. a chemical process in which the direction of optical rotation of a substance is reversed from dextrorotatory to levorotary or vice versa\n4. (genetics\n5. the reversal of the normal order of words\n6. (counterpoint\n7. a term formerly used to mean taking on the gender role of the opposite sex\n8. turning upside down; setting on end\n9. the act of turning inside out\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. Subversion (n.) means an overthrow, as from the foundation."
      },
      "21": {
        "Question": ".21.The story\u2019s bitter antagonist felt such great ______ for all of the othercharacters that as a result, his life was very lonely and he died alone.a. insurgenceb. malevolencec. reciprocationd. declamatione. preference",
        "c": {
          "option": "reciprocation",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the act of making or doing something in return\n2. alternating back-and-forth movement\n3. mutual interaction; the activity of reciprocating or exchanging (especially information\n"
        },
        "a": {
          "option": "insurgence",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an organized rebellion aimed at overthrowing a constituted government through the use of subversion and armed conflict\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "malevolence",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. wishing evil to others\n2. the quality of threatening evil\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "declamation",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. vehement oratory\n2. recitation of a speech from memory with studied gestures and intonation as an exercise in elocution or rhetoric\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "preference",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a strong liking\n2. a predisposition in favor of something\n3. the right or chance to choose\n4. grant of favor or advantage to one over another (especially to a country or countries in matters of international trade, such as levying duties\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. Malevolence (n.) means ill will or malice toward others; hate."
      },
      "22": {
        "Question": ".22.It is dif\ufb01cult to believe that charging 20% on an outstanding creditcard balance isn\u2019t ______!a. bankruptcyb. usuryc. noviced. kleptomaniae. \ufb02agrancy",
        "c": {
          "option": "novice",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. someone who has entered a religious order but has not taken final vows\n2. someone new to a field or activity\n"
        },
        "a": {
          "option": "bankruptcy",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a state of complete lack of some abstract property\n2. inability to discharge all your debts as they come due\n3. a legal process intended to insure equality among the creditors of a corporation declared to be insolvent\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "usury",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an exorbitant or unlawful rate of interest\n2. the act of lending money at an exorbitant rate of interest\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "kleptomania",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an irresistible impulse to steal in the absence of any economic motive\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "\ufb02agrancy",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "Answer": "b. Usury (n.) is the lending of money at exorbitant interest rates."
      },
      "23": {
        "Question": ".23.The ______ weather patterns of the tropical island meant touristshad to carry both umbrellas and sunglasses.a. impertinentb. supplicantc. preeminentd. illustrativee. kaleidoscopic",
        "a": {
          "option": "impertinent",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by a lightly pert and exuberant quality\n2. not pertinent to the matter under consideration\n3. improperly forward or bold\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "supplicant",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. someone who prays to God\n2. one praying humbly for something\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. humbly entreating\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "preeminent",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. greatest in importance or degree or significance or achievement\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "illustrative",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. clarifying by use of examples\n2. serving to demonstrate\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "kaleidoscopic",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. continually shifting or rapidly changing\n"
        },
        "Answer": "e. Kaleidoscopic (adj.) means continually changing or quicklyshifting."
      },
      "24": {
        "Question": ".24.Wedding ceremonies often include the exchange of ______ ringsto symbolize the couple\u2019s promises to each other.a. hirsuteb. acrimoniousc. plaintived. deciduouse. votive",
        "a": {
          "option": "hirsute",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having or covered with hair\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "acrimonious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by strong resentment or cynicism\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "plaintive",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. expressing sorrow\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "deciduous",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. (of plants and shrubs\n2. (of teeth, antlers, etc.\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "votive",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. dedicated in fulfillment of a vow\n"
        },
        "Answer": "e. Votive (adj.) means dedicated by a vow."
      },
      "25": {
        "Question": ".25.Kym was ______ in choosing her friends, so her parties wereattended by vastly different and sometimes bizarre personalities.a. indispensableb. indiscriminatec. commensurated. propulsivee. indisputable6",
        "a": {
          "option": "indispensable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not to be dispensed with; essential\n2. absolutely necessary; vitally necessary\n3. unavoidable\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "indiscriminate",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. failing to make or recognize distinctions\n2. not marked by fine distinctions\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "commensurate",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. corresponding in size or degree or extent\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "propulsive",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having the power to propel\n2. tending to or capable of propelling\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "indisputable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not open to question; obviously true\n2. impossible to doubt or dispute\n3. or sure\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. Indiscriminate (adj.) means not discriminating or choosingrandomly; haphazard; without distinction.8501 Sentence Completion Questions"
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "Chapter 2": {
      "26": {
        "Question": ".26.Phillip\u2019s ______ tone endeared him to his comical friends, butirritated his serious father.a. aloofb. jestingc. graved. earneste. conservative",
        "a": {
          "option": "aloof",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. remote in manner\nAdverb meaning(s):\n1. in an aloof manner\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "jesting",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. tell a joke; speak humorously\n2. act in a funny or teasing way\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by jokes and good humor\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "grave",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. death of a person\n2. a place for the burial of a corpse (especially beneath the ground and marked by a tombstone\n3. a mark (`\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. shape (a material like stone or wood\n2. carve, cut, or etch into a material or surface\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. dignified and somber in manner or character and committed to keeping promises\n2. causing fear or anxiety by threatening great harm\n3. of great gravity or crucial import; requiring serious thought\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "earnest",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something of value given by one person to another to bind a contract\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by a firm and humorless belief in the validity of your opinions\n2. sincerely earnest\n3. not distracted by anything unrelated to the goal\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "conservative",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a person who is reluctant to accept changes and new ideas\n2. a member of a Conservative Party\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. resistant to change, particularly in relation to politics or religion\n2. having social or political views favoring conservatism\n3. avoiding excess\n4. unimaginatively conventional\n5. conforming to the standards and conventions of the middle class\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. Jesting (adj.) means characterized by making jests; joking;playful."
      },
      "27": {
        "Question": ".27.Brian\u2019s pale Irish skin was ______ to burn if he spent too muchtime in the sun.a. proneb. urbanec. eminentd. erecte. dauntedChapter 2",
        "a": {
          "option": "prone",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having a tendency (to\n2. lying face downward\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "urbane",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. showing a high degree of refinement and the assurance that comes from wide social experience\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "eminent",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. standing above others in quality or position\n2. of imposing height; especially standing out above others\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "erect",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. construct, build, or erect\n2. cause to rise up\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. upright in position or posture\n2. of sexual organs; stiff and rigid\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "daunted",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to lose courage\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. caused to show discomposure\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. Prone (adj.) means a tendency or inclination to something."
      },
      "28": {
        "Question": ".28.A fan of historical \ufb01ction, Joline is now reading a novel aboutslavery in the ______ South.a. decorousb. roguec. drolld. antebellume. onerous",
        "a": {
          "option": "decorous",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by propriety and dignity and good taste in manners and conduct\n2. according with custom or propriety\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "rogue",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a deceitful and unreliable scoundrel\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "droll",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. comical in an odd or whimsical manner\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "antebellum",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. belonging to a period before a war especially the American Civil War\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "onerous",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not easily borne; wearing\n"
        },
        "Answer": "d. Antebellum (adj.) means belonging to the period before a war,especially the American Civil War."
      },
      "29": {
        "Question": ".29.Over the years the Wilsons slowly ______ upon the Jacksons\u2019property, moving the stone markers that divided their lots fartherand farther onto the Jacksons\u2019 land.a. encroachedb. jettisonedc. conjoinedd. repudiatede. teemed",
        "a": {
          "option": "encroached",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. advance beyond the usual limit\n2. impinge or infringe upon\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "jettisoned",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. throw away, of something encumbering\n2. throw as from an airplane\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "conjoined",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make contact or come together\n2. take in marriage\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. consisting of two or more associated entities\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "repudiated",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cast off\n2. refuse to acknowledge, ratify, or recognize as valid\n3. refuse to recognize or pay\n4. reject as untrue, unfounded, or unjust\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "teemed",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. be teeming, be abuzz\n2. move in large numbers\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. To encroach (v.) means to gradually or stealthily take the rightsor possessions of another; to advance beyond proper or formallimits; trespass."
      },
      "30": {
        "Question": ".30.Mary became ______ at typing because she practiced every day forsix months.a. pro\ufb01cientb. re\ufb02ectivec. dormantd. redundante. valiant",
        "a": {
          "option": "pro\ufb01cient",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "re\ufb02ective",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "dormant",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. in a condition of biological rest or suspended animation\n2. (of e.g. volcanos\n3. lying with head on paws as if sleeping\n4. inactive but capable of becoming active\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "redundant",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. more than is needed, desired, or required\n2. or unnecessary\n3. repetition of same sense in different words\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "valiant",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having or showing valor\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. Pro\ufb01cient (adj.) means well versed in any business or branch oflearning; adept."
      },
      "31": {
        "Question": ".31.To \ufb01nd out what her husband bought for her birthday, Susanattempted to ______ his family members about his recent shoppingexcursions.a. prescribeb. probec. alienated. convergee. revere10",
        "a": {
          "option": "prescribe",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. issue commands or orders for\n2. recommend as beneficial\n3. (medicine\n4. a treatment, medicine, etc.\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "revere",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. American silversmith remembered for his midnight ride (celebrated in a poem by Longfellow\n2. 1735-1818\n3. a lapel on a woman's garment; turned back to show the reverse side\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. love unquestioningly and uncritically or to excess; venerate as an idol\n2. regard with feelings of respect and reverence; consider hallowed or exalted or be in awe of\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "probe",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an inquiry into unfamiliar or questionable activities\n2. a flexible slender surgical instrument with a blunt end that is used to explore wounds or body cavities\n3. an exploratory action or expedition\n4. an investigation conducted using a flexible surgical instrument to explore an injury or a body cavity\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. question or examine thoroughly and closely\n2. examine physically with or as if with a probe\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "alienate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. arouse hostility or indifference in where there had formerly been love, affection, or friendliness\n2. transfer property or ownership\n3. make withdrawn or isolated or emotionally dissociated\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "converge",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. be adjacent or come together\n2. approach a limit as the number of terms increases without limit\n3. move or draw together at a certain location\n4. come together so as to form a single product\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. To probe (v.) is to examine thoroughly; tentatively survey."
      },
      "32": {
        "Question": ".32.Juan\u2019s friends found him in a ______ mood after he learned hewould be homecoming king.a. jovialb. stealthyc. paltryd. gulliblee. depleted",
        "a": {
          "option": "jovial",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. full of or showing high-spirited merriment\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "stealthy",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by quiet and caution and secrecy; taking pains to avoid being observed\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "paltry",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not worth considering\n2. contemptibly small in amount\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "gullible",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. naive and easily deceived or tricked\n2. easily tricked because of being too trusting\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "depleted",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. use up (resources or materials\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. no longer sufficient\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. Jovial (adj.) means showing hearty good cheer; marked with thespirit of jolly merriment."
      },
      "33": {
        "Question": ".33.His suit of armor made the knight ______ to his enemy\u2019s attack,and he was able to escape safely to his castle.a. vulnerableb. churlishc. invulnerabled. statice. imprudent",
        "a": {
          "option": "vulnerable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. susceptible to attack\n2. susceptible to criticism or persuasion or temptation\n3. capable of being wounded or hurt\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "churlish",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. rude and boorish\n2. having a bad disposition; surly\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "invulnerable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. immune to attack; impregnable\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "static",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a crackling or hissing noise caused by electrical interference\n2. angry criticism\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. not in physical motion\n2. concerned with or producing or caused by static electricity\n3. showing little if any change\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "imprudent",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not prudent or wise\n2. lacking wise self-restraint\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. Invulnerable (adj.) means incapable of being damaged orwounded; unassailable or invincible."
      },
      "34": {
        "Question": ".34.Choosing a small, fuel-ef\ufb01cient car is a ______ purchase for arecent college graduate.a. corruptb. tediousc. unhallowedd. sardonice. judicious",
        "a": {
          "option": "corrupt",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. corrupt morally or by intemperance or sensuality\n2. make illegal payments to in exchange for favors or influence\n3. place under suspicion or cast doubt upon\n4. alter from the original\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. lacking in integrity\n2. not straight; dishonest or immoral or evasive\n3. containing errors or alterations\n4. touched by rot or decay\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "tedious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. so lacking in interest as to cause mental weariness\n2. using or containing too many words\n3. or windy\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "unhallowed",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. remove the consecration from a person or an object\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. not hallowed or consecrated\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "sardonic",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. disdainfully or ironically humorous; scornful and mocking\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "judicious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by the exercise of good judgment or common sense in practical matters\n"
        },
        "Answer": "e. Judicious (adj.) means being wise or prudent; showing goodjudgment; sensible."
      },
      "35": {
        "Question": ".35.Such a ______ violation of school policy should be punished bynothing less than expulsion.a. copiousb. \ufb02agrantc. raucousd. nominale. morose",
        "a": {
          "option": "copious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. large in number or quantity (especially of discourse\n2. affording an abundant supply\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "\ufb02agrant",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "raucous",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. unpleasantly loud and harsh\n2. disturbing the public peace; loud and rough\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "nominal",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a phrase that can function as the subject or object of a verb\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. relating to or constituting or bearing or giving a name\n2. insignificantly small; a matter of form only (`tokenish' is informal\n3. pertaining to a noun or to a word group that functions as a noun\n4. of, relating to, or characteristic of an amount that is not adjusted for inflation\n5. named; bearing the name of a specific person\n6. existing in name only\n7. or titular\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "morose",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. showing a brooding ill humor\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. Flagrant (adj.) means conspicuously and outrageously bad,offensive, or reprehensible."
      },
      "36": {
        "Question": ".36.With all of the recent negative events in her life, she felt ______forces must be at work.a. resurgentb. prematurec. malignantd. punctiliouse. antecedent",
        "a": {
          "option": "resurgent",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. rising again as to new life and vigor\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "premature",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. born after a gestation period of less than the normal time\n2. too soon or too hasty\n3. uncommonly early or before the expected time\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "malignant",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. dangerous to health; characterized by progressive and uncontrolled growth (especially of a tumor\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "punctilious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by precise accordance with details\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "antecedent",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. someone from whom you are descended (but usually more remote than a grandparent\n2. a preceding occurrence or cause or event\n3. anything that precedes something similar in time\n4. the referent of an anaphor; a phrase or clause that is referred to by an anaphoric pronoun\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. preceding in time or order\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. Malignant (adj.) means disposed to cause distress or in\ufb02ictsuffering intentionally; inclining to produce death; an injuriousin\ufb01ltration."
      },
      "37": {
        "Question": ".37.The ______ rumors did a great deal of damage even though theyturned out to be false.a. bemusedb. prosaicc. apocryphald. ebulliente. tantamount",
        "a": {
          "option": "bemused",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to be confused emotionally\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. deeply absorbed in thought\n2. perplexed by many conflicting situations or statements; filled with bewilderment\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "prosaic",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not fanciful or imaginative\n2. lacking wit or imagination\n3. not challenging; dull and lacking excitement\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "apocryphal",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. being of questionable authenticity\n2. of or belonging to the Apocrypha\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "ebullient",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. joyously unrestrained\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "tantamount",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. being essentially equal to something\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. Apocryphal (adj.) means of questionable authenticity or doubtfulauthority; \ufb01ctitious, false."
      },
      "38": {
        "Question": ".38.When her schoolwork got to be too much, Pam had a tendency to______, which always put her further behind.a. dedicateb. rejuvenatec. ponderd. excele. procrastinate",
        "a": {
          "option": "dedicate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give entirely to a specific person, activity, or cause\n2. open to public use, as of a highway, park, or building\n3. inscribe or address by way of compliment\n4. set apart to sacred uses with solemn rites, of a church\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "rejuvenate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause (a stream or river\n2. develop youthful topographical features\n3. make younger or more youthful\n4. return to life; get or give new life or energy\n5. become young again\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "ponder",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. reflect deeply on a subject\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "excel",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. distinguish oneself\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "procrastinate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. postpone doing what one should be doing\n2. postpone or delay needlessly\n"
        },
        "Answer": "e. To procrastinate (v.) is to put off from day to day.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
      },
      "39": {
        "Question": ".39.Racha\u2019s glance was a ______ invitation to speak later in privateabout events of the meeting.a. trecherousb. scintillatingc. tactfuld. tacite. taboo",
        "a": {
          "option": "trecherous",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "scintillating",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give off\n2. reflect brightly\n3. emit or reflect light in a flickering manner\n4. physics: fluoresce momentarily when struck by a charged particle or high-energy photon\n5. be lively or brilliant or exhibit virtuosity\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. brilliantly clever\n2. marked by high spirits or excitement\n3. having brief brilliant points or flashes of light\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "tactful",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having or showing a sense of what is fitting and considerate in dealing with others\n2. showing skill and sensitivity in dealing with people\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "tacit",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. implied by or inferred from actions or statements\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "taboo",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a prejudice (especially in Polynesia and other South Pacific islands\n2. an inhibition or ban resulting from social custom or emotional aversion\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. declare as sacred and forbidden\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. excluded from use or mention\n2. forbidden to profane use especially in South Pacific islands\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. Tacit (adj.) means unspoken yet understood."
      },
      "40": {
        "Question": ".40.She reached the ______ of her career with her fourth novel, whichwon the Pulitzer Prize.a. harbingerb. apogeec. metamorphosisd. dictume. synthesis",
        "a": {
          "option": "harbinger",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something that precedes and indicates the approach of something or someone\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. foreshadow or presage\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "apogee",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a final climactic stage\n2. apoapsis in Earth orbit; the point in its orbit where a satellite is at the greatest distance from the Earth\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "metamorphosis",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the marked and rapid transformation of a larva into an adult that occurs in some animals\n2. a striking change in appearance or character or circumstances\n3. a complete change of physical form or substance especially as by magic or witchcraft\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "dictum",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an authoritative declaration\n2. an opinion voiced by a judge on a point of law not directly bearing on the case in question and therefore not binding\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "synthesis",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the process of producing a chemical compound (usually by the union of simpler chemical compounds\n2. the combination of ideas into a complex whole\n3. reasoning from the general to the particular (or from cause to effect\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. Apogee (n.) means the highest or farthest point, culmination; thepoint in its orbit where a satellite is at the greatest distance fromthe body it is orbiting."
      },
      "41": {
        "Question": ".41.The ______ townspeople celebrated the soldier\u2019s return to hishome by adorning trees with yellow ribbons and balloons.a. somberb. jubilantc. pitilessd. cunninge. unsullied12",
        "a": {
          "option": "somber",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. lacking brightness or color; dull\n2. grave or even gloomy in character\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "jubilant",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. joyful and proud especially because of triumph or success\n2. full of high-spirited delight\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "pitiless",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. without mercy or pity\n2. deficient in humane and kindly feelings\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "cunning",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. shrewdness as demonstrated by being skilled in deception\n2. crafty artfulness (especially in deception\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. attractive especially by means of smallness or prettiness or quaintness\n2. marked by skill in deception\n3. showing inventiveness and skill\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "unsullied",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. spotlessly clean and fresh\n2. (of reputation\n"
        },
        "Answer": "b. Jubilant (adj.) means rejoicing; expressing joyfulness; exulting."
      },
      "42": {
        "Question": ".42.The governor-elect was hounded by a group of ______ lobbyistsand others hoping to gain favor with her administration.a. facetiousb. abstrusec. magnanimousd. fawninge. saccharine",
        "a": {
          "option": "facetious",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. cleverly amusing in tone\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "abstruse",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. difficult to penetrate; incomprehensible to one of ordinary understanding or knowledge\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "magnanimous",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. noble and generous in spirit\n2. generous and understanding and tolerant\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "fawning",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. show submission or fear\n2. try to gain favor by cringing or flattering\n3. have fawns\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. attempting to win favor from influential people by flattery\n2. attempting to win favor by flattery\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "saccharine",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. overly sweet\n"
        },
        "Answer": "d. Fawning (adj.) means attempting to win favor or attention byexcessive \ufb02attery, ingratiating displays of affection, or servilecompliance; obsequious."
      },
      "43": {
        "Question": ".43.The mock graduation ceremony\u2014with a trained skunk posing asthe college president\u2014was a complete ______ that offended manycollege of\ufb01cials.a. tempestb. epitomec. quintessenced. travestye. recitative",
        "c": {
          "option": "quintessence",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the fifth and highest element after air and earth and fire and water; was believed to be the substance composing all heavenly bodies\n2. the purest and most concentrated essence of something\n3. the most typical example or representative of a type\n"
        },
        "a": {
          "option": "tempest",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a violent commotion or disturbance\n2. (literary\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "epitome",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a standard or typical example\n2. a brief abstract (as of an article or book\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "travesty",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a comedy characterized by broad satire and improbable situations\n2. a composition that imitates or misrepresents somebody's style, usually in a humorous way\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. make a travesty of\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "recitative",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a vocal passage of narrative text that a singer delivers with natural rhythms of speech\n"
        },
        "Answer": "d. Travesty (n.) means a parody; a grotesque imitation with theintent to ridicule."
      },
      "44": {
        "Question": ".44.The busy, ______ fabric of the clown\u2019s tie matched his oversizedjacket, which was equally atrocious.a. mottledb. bleakc. credibled. malleablee. communicable",
        "a": {
          "option": "mottled",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. mark with spots or blotches of different color or shades of color as if stained\n2. colour with streaks or blotches of different shades\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having spots or patches of color\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "bleak",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. offering little or no hope\n2. providing no shelter or sustenance\n3. unpleasantly cold and damp\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "credible",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. capable of being believed\n2. (a common but incorrect usage where `credulous' would be appropriate\n3. appearing to merit belief or acceptance\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "malleable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. easily influenced\n2. capable of being shaped or bent or drawn out\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "communicable",
          "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. (of disease\n2. readily communicated\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. Mottled (adj.) means blotched or spotted with different colors orshades."
      },
      "45": {
        "Question": ".45.Kendrick\u2019s talent ______ under the tutelage of Anya Kowalonek,who as a young woman had been the most accomplished pianist inher native Lithuania.a. banteredb. toutedc. \ufb02ourishedd. embellishede. colluded",
        "a": {
          "option": "bantered",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. be silly or tease one another\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "touted",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. advertize in strongly positive terms\n2. show off\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "\ufb02ourished",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "embellished",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. add details to\n2. be beautiful to look at\n3. make more attractive by adding ornament, colour, etc.\n4. make more beautiful\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "colluded",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. act in unison or agreement and in secret towards a deceitful or illegal purpose\n"
        },
        "Answer": "c. To \ufb02ourish (v.) is (of artists) to be in a state of high productivity,excellence, or in\ufb02uence; to grow luxuriously, thrive; to fare well,prosper, increase in wealth, honor, comfort or whatever isdesirable; to make bold, sweeping movements."
      },
      "46": {
        "Question": ".46.The children were ______ by the seemingly nonsensical clues untilKinan pointed out that the messages were in code.a. censuredb. striatedc. feignedd. prevaricatede. \ufb02ummoxed",
        "a": {
          "option": "censured",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. rebuke formally\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "striated",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. mark with striae or striations\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "feigned",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make believe with the intent to deceive\n2. make a pretence of\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. not genuine\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "prevaricated",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. be deliberately ambiguous or unclear in order to mislead or withhold information\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "\ufb02ummoxed",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "Answer": "e. To \ufb02ummox (v.) is to confuse, perplex, bewilder."
      },
      "47": {
        "Question": ".47.As the ______ in Romeo and Juliet, Romeo is a hero able tocapture the audience\u2019s sympathy by continually professing his lovefor Juliet.a. protagonistb. enigmac. facaded. activiste. catechist",
        "c": {
          "option": "facade",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the face or front of a building\n2. a showy misrepresentation intended to conceal something unpleasant\n"
        },
        "a": {
          "option": "protagonist",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a person who backs a politician or a team etc.\n2. the principal character in a work of fiction\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "enigma",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something that baffles understanding and cannot be explained\n2. a difficult problem\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "activist",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a militant reformer\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. advocating or engaged in activism\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "catechist",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. one who instructs catechumens in preparation for baptism (especially one using a catechism\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. A protagonist (n.) is the main character in a drama."
      },
      "48": {
        "Question": ".48.The chess master promised to ______ havoc upon his opponent\u2019spawns for taking his bishop.a. wreakb. warrantc. ensued. placatee. endow",
        "a": {
          "option": "wreak",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to happen or to occur as a consequence\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "warrant",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a writ from a court commanding police to perform specified acts\n2. a type of security issued by a corporation (usually together with a bond or preferred stock\n3. formal and explicit approval\n4. a written assurance that some product or service will be provided or will meet certain specifications\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. provide adequate grounds to justify (a certain course of action\n2. stand behind and guarantee the quality, accuracy, or condition of\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "ensue",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. issue or terminate (in a specified way, state, etc.\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "placate",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to be more favorably inclined; gain the good will of\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "endow",
          "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give qualities or abilities to\n2. furnish with an endowment\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. To wreak (v.) means to in\ufb02ict, as a revenge or punishment."
      },
      "49": {
        "Question": ".49.I have always admired Seymour\u2019s ______; I\u2019ve never seen himrattled by anything.a. aplombb. con\ufb02uencec. proprietyd. compunctione. nostalgia",
        "a": {
          "option": "aplomb",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. great coolness and composure under strain\n"
        },
        "b": {
          "option": "con\ufb02uence",
          "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "propriety",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. correct or appropriate behavior\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "compunction",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a feeling of deep regret (usually for some misdeed\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "nostalgia",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. longing for something past\n"
        },
        "Answer": "a. Aplomb (n.) is self-assurance, composure, poise, especially understrain."
      },
      "50": {
        "Question": ".50.The soldiers received a military ______ to inspect all their vehiclesbefore traveling.a. allotmentb. dominionc. affectationd. calculatione. mandate14",
        "b": {
          "option": "dominion",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. dominance or power through legal authority\n2. a region marked off for administrative or other purposes\n3. one of the self-governing nations in the British Commonwealth\n"
        },
        "a": {
          "option": "allotment",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a share set aside for a specific purpose\n2. the act of distributing by allotting or apportioning; distribution according to a plan\n"
        },
        "c": {
          "option": "affectation",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a deliberate pretense or exaggerated display\n"
        },
        "d": {
          "option": "calculation",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the procedure of calculating; determining something by mathematical or logical methods\n2. problem solving that involves numbers or quantities\n3. planning something carefully and intentionally\n"
        },
        "e": {
          "option": "mandate",
          "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a document giving an official instruction or command\n2. a territory surrendered by Turkey or Germany after World War I and put under the tutelage of some other European power until they are able to stand by themselves\n3. the commission that is given to a government and its policies through an electoral victory\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. assign under a mandate\n2. make mandatory\n3. assign authority to\n"
        },
        "Answer": "e. Mandate (n.) is a command or authoritative instruction.16501 Sentence Completion Questions"
      }
    }
  }
]
